Erin Chen

SUMMARY

Detail- and quality-oriented Language, Media, and Communications major currently attending the University of Rochester, with 2 years of work experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of brand management, community outreach, and creative services skills to successfully ensure strong brand presence.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

OPERATION SMILE - Social Media Intern

CUPERTINO, CA • 07/2020 - Current

- Conducted competitive analysis of various non-profit organizations, focusing on audience growth, engagement, and activity.
- Conducted interviews and developed blog posts that focused on #YOTN, patients, and Operation Smile's mission.
- Assisted with organizing the 2020-21 social media calendar, as well as brainstorming
 ways to increase audience engagement and capitalizing relevant trends.
- Worked on marketing and social media campaigns for international holidays in order to increase fundraising efforts, with companies such as Stryker and Lays.

AMERICAN RED CROSS - Social Media Intern

NEW YORK, NY • 06/2020 - 08/2020

- Developed the weekly #ICYMI newsletter, focusing on weekly highlights, emergency assistance statistics, and upcoming events.
- Assisted with the #MyRedCrossLife Instagram series by scheduling, conducting, and transcribing interviews with Red Cross volunteers.

CAUSEWAVE COMMUNITY PARTNERS - Nonprofit Strategy & Marketing Intern $ROCHESTER, NY \bullet 01/2020 - 05/2020$

- Worked with representatives from marketing, advertising, and nonprofit organizations to implement various outreach activities to support a community impact initiative.
- Developed and implemented a social media plan for specific events and initiatives, in addition to synthesizing data from surveys with up to 600 responses, that allowed companies better their company culture and find more clients.
- Assisted in the delivery of quality programs to nonprofits, such as brand development and communications planning.

MOTHERLY - Social Media Intern & Community Manager

NEW YORK, NY • 09/2019 - 02/2020

- Identified editorial content to re-package and re-promote according to real-time trends for Motherly and competitor brands, in order to improve traffic and community engagement.
- Pulled and compiled weekly + monthly analytics reports from Pinterest and Instagram, and assisted with weekly and monthly content performance reports, focusing on page views, engagement, and impressions.
- Designed Pinterest and Instagram posts, and sourced images from influencers and hashtags that match the Motherly brand, and increased Pinterest follower count from 19k to over 23k, and Instagram follower count from 450k to over 500k.

CONTACT

echen25@u.rochester.edu (408) 318-8828 Cupertino, CA 95014

SKILLS

- · Social Media Marketing
- Search Engine Optimization
- · Copywriting and Editing
- · Content Strategy
- English Native
- Mandarin Fluent
- Applications: Google Analytics, Hootsuite, Dash Hudson, Sprout Social, Parsely, Trello, Buzzsumo, Wordpress, Microsoft Office

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts (B.A): Language, Media, And Communications University of Rochester Rochester, NY • Expected in 12/2020

- Minor in Music, Piano Performance
- · Minor in Creative Writing